foreflight.com 2018-11-25

# ForeFlight - Privacy

This Privacy Policy is incorporated by reference into the ForeFlight End User License Agreement (“EULA”). The terms “ForeFlight,” “we,” and “us” include ForeFlight LLC and our affiliates and subsidiaries. The Privacy Policy explains how ForeFlight may collect, use, and disclose information we obtain through the “Service.” Any capitalized terms used and not defined in this Privacy Policy shall have the meaning given to them in the EULA.

**IMPORTANT NOTE:** By accessing or using the Service, you expressly consent to ForeFlight’s collection, use, and disclosure of your Personal Information in accordance with the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy is incorporated into and subject to the terms of the EULA.

## Categories of Personal Data Processed by ForeFlight

#### PERSONAL DATA THAT IS PROCESSED WHEN YOU CREATE A FOREFLIGHT ACCOUNT:

When you create a ForeFlight account, we ask you to provide your email address and name.

**PURPOSES AND LEGAL GROUNDS:**

(a) ForeFlight processes your email address because you use your email address and your password to sign in to your account. The legal ground for processing your email address for this purpose is based on ForeFlight’s legitimate interest in protecting the security of your account.

(b) ForeFlight also processes your email address for the purpose of sending you important information about your ForeFlight products, apps or account, such as important safety information or material changes to this Privacy Policy. The name you provide is associated with your account profile. The legal ground for processing your email address and name for these purposes is ForeFlight’s legitimate interest in providing you important safety or other information about your ForeFlight products, apps or account or material changes to this Privacy Policy.

(c) For EU citizens, if you provide your opt-in consent to receiving marketing information from ForeFlight, ForeFlight will also process your email address for the purpose of sending you marketing information about ForeFlight products and apps, newsletters, and other occasional emails. For non-EU citizens, by giving ForeFlight your email address, you consent to receiving marketing information from ForeFlight and ForeFlight will also process your email address for the purpose of sending you marketing information about ForeFlight products and apps, newsletters, and other occasional emails. The legal ground for processing your email address for this purpose is your consent. You may withdraw your consent at any time by changing your preferences in your ForeFlight account or through the unsubscribe link at the bottom of our marketing emails. The marketing emails you receive from ForeFlight are based on the preferences you provide in your ForeFlight account, the locale indicated by your Internet Protocol (IP) address, the types of ForeFlight devices you have added to your ForeFlight account, and any subscriptions included in your ForeFlight account. The legal ground for processing this data for this purpose is ForeFlight’s legitimate interest in reducing the number of marketing emails sent to each particular customer by selecting which customers receive a particular marketing email rather than sending every marketing email to every customer who has consented to receiving marketing emails.

(d) ForeFlight also processes your email address to associate it with your ForeFlight account when you interact with our customer support representatives. The legal ground for this processing is our legitimate interest in providing quality customer support.

#### PERSONAL DATA THAT IS PROCESSED WHEN YOU MAKE A PAYMENT:

When you make payments through the Service, you may need to provide financial account information, such as your credit card number or bank account information, to our third-party payment processors. This information is provided directly to such payment processors, and we do not collect or store such information, though we may receive summary information about transactions that does not include credit card or bank account numbers.

**PURPOSES AND LEGAL GROUNDS:**

The legal ground for processing this data for these purposes is performance of a contract. We also process your personal data as part of our fraud detection processes. The legal ground for processing your personal data for that purpose is our legitimate interest in protecting ForeFlight and our customers from attempts to engage in fraudulent transactions.

Your financial account information, such as your credit card, is required to make a payment for a product. The legal ground for processing your email address for this purpose is based on ForeFlight’s legitimate interest in collecting payment for its services.

#### PERSONAL DATA THAT IS PROCESSED WHEN YOU ADD AN AIRCRAFT TO YOUR FOREFLIGHT PROFILE:

When you add an aircraft to your ForeFlight account, we may ask for additional information, such as the make, model, series name, tail number, year and serial number of the aircraft.

**PURPOSES AND LEGAL GROUNDS:**

This information is processed to help ForeFlight function better by understanding the performance of your aircraft and allowing ForeFlight to make better calculations about your flight. The legal ground for processing this information is our legitimate interest in providing a better product that incorporates the performance of your aircraft in making calculations.

#### PERSONAL DATA THAT IS PROCESSED WHEN YOU USE FOREFLIGHT TO CREATE AND FILE FLIGHT PLANS:

You can use ForeFlight to create flight plans and file those flight plans with applicable aviation authorities. When you do this, we process your name and address, aircraft details, date and time of the flight, and associated flight details.

**PURPOSES AND LEGAL GROUNDS:**

This information is processed to help you create flight plans and file them with applicable aviation authorities. The legal ground for processing this information is our legitimate interest in providing a tool to our customers to create and file flight plans.

#### PERSONAL DATA THAT IS PROCESSED USING THE LOCATION INFORMATION FROM YOUR MOBILE DEVICE:

When you use ForeFlight, we process the aircraft’s tail number, latitude, longitude, heading, barometric altitude, destination, estimated time enroute, and associated flight details. Without location information, ForeFlight navigational features will not function properly. This data is uploaded to your ForeFlight account.

**PURPOSES AND LEGAL GROUNDS:**

This information is processed to help you keep track of important details regarding your flights. The legal ground for processing this information is our legitimate interest in providing a tool to our customers to keep track of important flight details. In addition, ForeFlight’s navigational features help provide you with a safer flight.

#### PERSONAL DATA THAT IS PROCESSED WHEN YOU USE THE LOGBOOK FEATURE:

When you use the logbook feature on ForeFlight, we process information about your flights, such as the take-off and landing airports, dates and times, and notes you choose to submit.

**PURPOSES AND LEGAL GROUNDS:**

We process this data to provide our customers an automated tool for them to maintain these regulatorily required records in their pilot logs. The legal ground for processing this information is our legitimate interest in provider our customers an automated tool for them to maintain these regulatorily required records in their pilot logs.

#### PERSONAL DATA THAT IS PROCESSED WHEN YOU USE THE APPLICATION:

When you use the ForeFlight app, we process information about you and your device including a device ID, IP address, mobile software and hardware information, pages or areas visited within the Service, what time said pages and areas are visited, and web browser information, so that we can provide and customize functionality, such as push notifications. You may also permit the Service to access your device’s contact list and photo storage. We may share information about your flight plan and fuel card information to fuel vendors to obtain fuel pricing information.

**PURPOSES AND LEGAL GROUNDS:**

We process this data to provide our customers with a better user experience. The legal ground for processing this information is our legitimate interest in providing a better product that provides the user with a better experience.

#### PERSONAL DATA THAT IS PROCESSED WHEN YOU COMMUNICATE WITH FOREFLIGHT:

When you interact with our customer support representatives via email, telephone, or online, we collect personal data, such as your name, mailing address, phone number, email address, and contact preferences; and information about the ForeFlight products you own. We also may create event logs that are useful in diagnosing product or app performance-related issues, and capture information relating to the support or service issue. To improve customer service, subject to applicable laws, we may also record and review conversations with customer support representatives, and analyze any feedback provided to us through voluntary customer surveys.

**PURPOSES AND LEGAL GROUNDS:**

We use this information to provide you with customer and product support and to monitor the quality and types of customer and product support we provide to our customers. The legal ground for processing this information for these purposes is ForeFlight’s legitimate interests in providing quality product support.

#### PERSONAL DATA THAT IS PROCESSED WHEN YOU VISIT THE FOREFLIGHT CAREERS PAGE:

When you interact with our careers page, we collect information you provide in applying for a job, including information contained on resumes or other documentation voluntarily provided by you to us in the job application process.

**PURPOSES AND LEGAL GROUNDS:**

We use this information to evaluate you for a career at ForeFlight. The legal ground for processing this information for the purposes is ForeFlight’s legitimate interest in hiring qualified candidates.

## Categories of Recipients of Personal Data

#### AVIATION AUTHORITIES:

When you use ForeFlight to create and file flight plans, your flights plans and associated information are submitted to the applicable aviation authorities.

#### OTHER SERVICE PROVIDERS:

ForeFlight uses cloud services from third parties such as Vero and Zendesk, to assist in sending emails and to analyze the use and performance of ForeFlight products. Those services track the activities associated with emails, such as whether they were opened, whether links in the emails were clicked on, and whether purchases were made following clicks on those links. ForeFlight uses this data to analyze the level of engagement with its emails. ForeFlight uses third-party service providers such as HockeyApp and Segment to help us better understand usage of the ForeFlight website and the ForeFlight app.

#### OTHER DISCLOSURES:

We may disclose personal data about you to others: (a) if we have your valid consent to do so; (b) to comply with a valid subpoena, legal order, court order, legal process, or other legal obligation; (c) to enforce any of our terms and conditions or policies; or (d) as necessary to pursue available legal remedies or defend legal claims.

**Merger, Sale, or Other Asset Transfers**

If we are involved in a merger, acquisition, financing due diligence, reorganization, bankruptcy, receivership, sale of ForeFlight assets, or transition of service to another provider, your information may be sold or transferred as part of such a transaction as permitted by law and/or contract. We cannot control how such entities may use or disclose such information, and we disclaim any liability arising out of such entity’s failure to comply with the terms of the EULA or this Privacy Policy.

**Transfers of Personal Data**

ForeFlight is a global business. To offer our products, apps, and services, we may need to transfer your personal data to other ForeFlight companies in other countries. When you create a ForeFlight account, add personal data in your account profile, or upload data to your ForeFlight account, your personal data will be collected and stored on ForeFlight LLC’s servers in the United States. Personal data regarding individuals who reside in a country in the European Economic Area or in Switzerland is controlled by and processed by ForeFlight LLC.

Any transfers of personal data from ForeFlight companies in the European Economic Area ("EEA") or Switzerland to ForeFlight LLC in the United States is done pursuant to European Commission approved Model Contractual Clauses.

All ForeFlight companies are required to follow the privacy practices set forth in this Privacy Statement.

## Cookies and Similar Technologies

#### WEBSITE:

To help analyze how you and other visitors navigate the ForeFlight websites, we compile aggregate statistics about site usage and response rates to help diagnose any problems with ForeFlight’s servers, administer the ForeFlight websites, and maintain user experience continuity across website pages and site visits, we, with assistance from third-party analytics service providers, collect certain information when you visit our site. This information includes IP address, geographic location of the device, browser type, browser language, date and time of your request, time(s) of your visit(s), page views and page elements (e.g., links) that you click. We may use cookies, pixel tags, web beacons, clear GIFs or other similar tools on our sites or in our email messages to assist us in collecting and analyzing such information. We use this information to provide better, more relevant content on our sites, to identify and fix problems, and to improve your overall experience on our sites.

If you do not want information collected through the use of these technologies, there is a simple procedure in most browsers that allows you to automatically decline many of these technologies, or to be given the choice of declining or accepting them.

If you reside in the European Union or other jurisdiction that requires us to obtain your consent to use cookies on our sites, then you will have an opportunity to manage your cookie preferences on the sites; except that certain cookies are required to enable core site functionality, and you cannot choose to disable those cookies.

#### ForeFlight APP:

We also collect data from users about their usage of the ForeFlight app. The types of analytical information that are collected include the date and time the app accesses our servers, app version, the location of the device, language setting, what information and files have been downloaded to the app, user behavior (e.g., features used, frequency of use), device state information, device model, hardware and operating system information, and information relating to how the app functions. ForeFlight uses this data to improve the quality and functionality of the ForeFlight app; to develop and market products and features that best serve you and other users; and to help identify and fix app stability issues and other usability problems as quickly as possible.

The legal ground for processing this analytical information is our legitimate interest in understanding how our customers interact with our products, apps, and websites so we can enhance the user experience and functionality of our products, apps, and websites.

Here are examples of third-party providers of analytics and similar services we currently use:

#### ANALYTICS SERVICES:

**Segment:** This site uses Segment web analytics. Segment helps us measure and evaluate site usage behavior, such as mouse clicks, mouse movements, keystrokes (excluding personally identifiable information), scrolling activity, and pages visited and actions taken on the site and app. For more information, see the [Segment privacy policy](https://segment.com/docs/legal/privacy/).

**HockeyApp:** HockeyApp, which is a Microsoft service, is used to help us better understand usage of the ForeFlight app to improve user experience and to identify and resolve the root causes of app crashes. For more information, see the [Microsoft privacy policy](https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/PrivacyStatement).

**Google:** Google Analytics is used to track site statistics and user demographics, interests and behavior on websites. We also use Google Search Console to help understand how our website visitors find our website and to improve our search engine optimization. For more information, see the [Google privacy policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en). You may opt out at <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>.

**Mixpanel:** We use Mixpanel for data analytics. The information generated relating to our Service is used to create reports about the use of the Service. For more information, see the [Mixpanel privacy policy](https://mixpanel.com/legal/privacy-policy/). You may opt out at <https://mixpanel.com/optout/>.

## Information Security

We take steps to ensure that your information is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy. Unfortunately, the Internet cannot be guaranteed to be 100% secure, and we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you provide to us. Neither ForeFlight, nor its affiliates, nor any of their respective employees, officers or agents or the provider of the internet services on behalf of ForeFlight (nor any other person involved in the management or establishment of the Service) can give any representation or warranty as to the absolute security of the data transmitted using the Service, and cannot give any guarantee that such data will not be compromised by bad actors. If you choose to provide data to or allow collection of data by ForeFlight, then you do so understanding the aforementioned risk.

By using the Service or providing Personal Information to us, you agree that we may communicate with you electronically regarding security, privacy, and administrative issues relating to your use of the Service. If we learn of a security system’s breach, we may attempt to notify you electronically by posting a notice on the Service or sending an email to you. You may have a legal right to receive this notice by mail.

## Children’s Privacy

We do not knowingly collect, maintain, or use Personal Information from children under 13 years of age, and no part of the Service is directed to children under the age of 13. If you learn that your child has provided us with Personal Information without your consent, you may alert us at [team@foreflight.com](mailto:team@foreflight.com). If we learn that we have collected any Personal Information from children under 13 in a manner that is inconsistent with the U.S. Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act, we will promptly take steps to delete such information and terminate the child’s account as soon as practicable.

## Marketing

We do not rent, sell, or share Personal Information about you with other people or nonaffiliated companies for their direct marketing purposes, unless we have your permission. We may allow access to other data collected by the Service to send information we think may be useful or relevant to you. Note that we may use your name, usage history and email address without further consent for non-marketing or administrative purposes (such as notifying you of major updates, customer service needs, tips on using the Service, notifications of unused features of the Service, or items for which you have requested communication).

## Legal and Similar Disclosures

We may access, preserve, and disclose collected information, if we believe doing so is required or appropriate to: (i) comply with law enforcement requests and legal process, such as a court order or subpoena; (ii) respond to your requests; (iii) comply with the law; (iv) investigate, prevent, take action, or enforce compliance with regard to a violation of the EULA or this Privacy Policy; (v) investigate, prevent or take action regarding illegal activities or suspected fraud; or (vi) protect your, our, or others’ rights, property, or safety.

## Privacy Policy Updates

We may update this Privacy Policy from time to time as we add new products and apps, as we improve our current offerings and as technologies and laws change. You can determine when this Privacy Policy was last revised by referring to the “Last updated” legend at the top of this page. Any changes will become effective upon our posting of the revised Privacy Policy.

We will provide notice to you if these changes are material and, where required by applicable law, we will obtain your consent. This notice will be provided by email or by posting notice of the changes on the ForeFlight website and through the ForeFlight app.

## Retention of Personal Data

We will retain your personal data as long as your ForeFlight account is active. In addition, see below under “Your Rights” for a description of your right of erasure.

## Data Controller and Data Protection Officer

The personal data collected by ForeFlight is controlled by ForeFlight LLC’s Data Protection Officer at 2323 S. Shepherd Drive, Suite 912, Houston, TX 77019, which you can also contact by email at [team@foreflight.com](mailto:team@foreflight.com).

## Your Rights

If you reside in the European Union, you have the right under the General Data Protection Regulation to request from ForeFlight access to and rectification or erasure of your personal data, data portability, restriction of processing of your personal data, the right to object to processing of your personal data, and the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority. If you reside outside of the European Union, you may have similar rights under your local laws.

To request access to or rectification, portability or erasure of your personal data, or to delete your ForeFlight account, email [team@foreflight.com](mailto:team@foreflight.com)

If you live in the European Union and you wish to exercise your right to restriction of processing or your right to object to processing, contact ForeFlight’s Data Protection Officer at 2323 S. Shepherd Drive, Suite 912, Houston, TX 77019, which you can also contact by email at [team@foreflight.com](mailto:team@foreflight.com). If you do not live in the European Union but you believe you have a right to restriction of processing or a right to object to processing under your local laws, please contact ForeFlight LLC at [privacy@foreflight.com](mailto:privacy@foreflight.com).
